Charles Puente-Matos

New York, NY 10017 - 631.988.0913

GitHub: /puentebravo | Portfolio: charliepuente.com | Email: puentematos@gmail.com |

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/puentematos/

Full stack web developer leveraging a background in creative writing to tell better stories through expressive applications. Specializes in TypeScript, React, and Python. Creative, laterally thinking engineer with a passion for physical computing and interactive storytelling.

Technical Skills

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript ES6, SQL, Python, TypeScript

Applications: Github, Heroku, MongoAtlas, AWS, MS Azure, Gitlab, Docker

Tools: Node.js, Flask, Prisma, MongoDb, Jest, Express, React.js, GraphQL, Bootstrap, Tailwinds CSS

Relevant Experience

UK Department for Education | New York, NY (Remote) | 2022 – Present

Teaching Assistant, Front-End Skills Bootcamp

Picked as part of an initial cadre of developers in carrying out a UK Government-funded pilot program to train Front-end engineers.

- Developed new SOPs and best practices for future course iterations
- Supported the growth of over 100 students across multiple time zones through pair coding, one-onone mentorship, and on-call technical support

edX | New York, NY (Remote) | 2022 - Present

Tutor, Full Stack Web Development

Supports all edX Programming Bootcamps by privately tutoring students in need utilizing one-to-one mentoring, interactive lessons, and personal coaching.

- Improved learning outcomes for 3 5 students a week, strengthening understanding in a full stack curriculum that includes technologies across the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) Stack
- Create custom lesson plans tailored to a learner's needs and goals to further improve skills retention

Rutgers University / Columbia University | New York, NY (Remote) | 2021- Present

Teaching Assistant, Full Stack Web Development

Currently Responsible for aiding in the instruction of multiple 30-60 student online learning cohorts. In addition to assisting with class administrative duties, I take direct charge of a smaller group of students for indepth learning, mentorship, and advising.

- Prepare the next generation of web developers via small group learning, pair coding, and one-on-one instruction
- Study in demand frameworks and technologies to best prepare learners
- Maintain Gitlab repository each week to ensure learners get the most up to date materials

Freelance Full-Stack Web Developer / Tutor | New York, NY (Remote) | 2021- Present

Self-Employed Freelancer

Contracted to design, develop, and ship web modern web presences for private clients. To facilitate this, I keep in daily contact with the client, updating them on the current state of the project while also making sure development is progressing in line with their vision.

- Utilize leading front and backend tools, libraries, and technologies to create sites that are both performant and accessible
- Tutor private clients in web development techniques, concepts, and basic skills

Sussex Wines and Spirits | New York, NY | 2017 - 2020

Social Media & IT Systems Manager

Managed the critical systems, technical processes, and inventory data of a \$4,000,000 per year wine and spirits business. Additionally, I specialized in the sale of high-end Spirits, trained all new employees in company technical practices and systems, and directed our social media presence.

- Implemented new point of sale software and migrated a 10,000-entry inventory database
- Doubled social media engagement and follower count
- Mentored new employees to build staff redundancy

Education

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development Columbia University School of Engineering New York, NY

Bachelor of Arts, English Fordham University, New York, NY